Hello everyone.
This is a getting started guide
and an overview of the Semantic Data Hub.
You should already passed the onboarding.
Be part of a team instance
because then we are able to first clone a data product
and explore the Star Wars data product together,
which will allow you to see the model
and to see the graph workspace,
how this is all working together.
Let's dive right in.
First, you're landing on the sand sandbox.
You're getting to your settings here to my storage.
Here is the team instance.
I'm in the different team instance as you can see here.
Here's the data products that was, I could go in here
as well and see everything,
but please clone this data product.
We will do this by going into the settings.
I'm going here to my storage and I clone the data product.
I clone the data product from Host different.
The data point I want to clone is Star Wars.
I will keep the name, I will
rename the description to local data product
and I clone it.
Then we will land here again,
but we will see that Star Wars has been added.
Let's dive here in, and it's the local data product.
First, we are having one main branch here.
Let's add this to our bookmark here.
We're managing the contract graph graph.
We are adding a workspace pointer, star Wars main,
this branch, we are adding it
and now you can also exitus exit it here over the bookmark,
which is, comes quite in handy.
Let's dive into the data product here itself.
We will focus today on the people.
These are the all the types.
We are focused today on the people in Star Wars
and the film and the films.
Let's add them to the ontology view.
Here we are switching to the class diagram
to see also all the attributes here.
As you can see, they are connected to you
through the character
as we are having multiple people playing in one movie,
and um, one person is also playing in the movie here itself,
this will be the focus,
but I will show you all of the types C as well.
So we are just adding everything to the ontology view
and here we can, can see everything
as you can see the planet.
So also here modeled the movie
and, uh, species, starships and vehicle.
All right, so if we are going to the people,
we can see all of them.
If we would have any inherent records, this
Would just join them Pretty quick.
I just wanna focus on Obi Van and Luke Skywalker here.
I add them to the graph workspace,
and as you can see here are both my of my persons.
Now I want to see all of the movies that they're playing in
and see the connections there.
So I go to the films
and I just wanna select all with the command a shortcut,
and I add them as well to the graph workspace.
This right now looks not as clean, so
I do the layout selection to sort it a bit.
Then I also wanna toggle the type visibility
to make it easier to work with.
As you can see here, I can just drag and drop the types
and I can see the connections where Obiwan is playing,
where both are playing in, in what movie.
And I can get a nice overview here.
If I want to edit, uh, one of them,
I can just click on them.
I can edit them, I can view them, have the menu that
dive in here so I can see all of the labels.
For example, the Skywalker.
And I could just update the record here.
This was the first quick overview
and we will see how to, how to work with this in later.
Once.